Ivan Ivanov

ivan@ivanovs.info

Wellington, NZ

+64 22 121 3726

Software developer

I am a programmer with 10 years experience in software development. Recently I have been working mostly with Python and related web technologies (including backend, frontend and DevOps bits) in a telco environment, which also means some exposure to networking technologies.

Languages, tools, and technologies

Python, **C/C++**, JavaScript, Django, Pyramid, jQuery, EmberJS, Git, Hg, Docker, Ansible, Vagrant, Jenkins, Fabric, Oracle, MySQL, Postgresql, REST APIs, ...

Previous employment

Kordia Ltd. Nov 2015 – now

Wellington, New Zealand

Senior Software developer

Kordia is a government-owned telco company providing various network services for NZ and AU businesses. My responsibilities include supporting a wide range of custom-written network monitoring systems interacting with the multitude of nodes within the Kordia network. Most recently I have been working as the main backend programmer for the new customer portal, written in Python. I have managed to simplify certain parts of the existing code and reduce its size by a factor of 4, which resulted in the better performance and maintainability of the system in general.

Yellow Pages Ltd

Jan 2013 - Nov 2015

Auckland, New Zealand

Senior Python developer

My work involved a heavy interaction with the Google AdWords API, since Yellow is one of the few partners of Google which automate their processes of managing customer advertising campaigns with the API. I was responsible for delivering key features of the internal automated budgeting system and mentoring the junior members of the team.

Various software development jobs in Russia

2005 - 2012

My own projects

I find it very important to understand how things are built, that is why I work on various projects in my own time, in C++ and assembly. They include but are not limited to:

https://github.com/obiwanus/pcasm. An ongoing project in which I am making a MIPS-like processor, in Verilog + MIPS assembly, in order to gain a better understanding of the hardware.

https://github.com/obiwanus/editor. An extendable graphics testbed with a user interface inspired by Blender. Software rendering (no GPU), ray tracing, SIMD, multithreading, pure C++, no graphics libraries or frameworks used, native Linux and Windows support. Quick demo: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cqdyQezP9Ck.

https://github.com/obiwanus/emulator6502. A virtual machine, an emulator of the 6502 processor, and an assembler for the 6502 - I built it from scratch in C to play with the 6502 assembly language without having to learn the specifics of the Apple][or other systems.

Please visit my GitHub for more projects: https://github.com/obiwanus

Education

Bachelor of Engineering and Technology in Computer Science

Ural State Technical University, Yekaterinburg, Russia (2002-2006)